I don't like this.
（月子）　ヤダなぁ。
The most difficult is left behind.
一番難しいのが残るんだよね。
I think I don't have that much power.
（月子）　力ずくしかないのかなぁ。
Ah!
あっ。
That's unexpectedly easy
案外　簡単じゃん。
Power
力ずく。
At that time,
（深井平太）　ねぇ　あの時さ→
Who charged you?
誰が充電したの？
How come you were completely charged quickly?
何で　あんな早く　充電できたの？
I don't remember.
（Ｑ１０）　はて？ メモリーが残っていません。
You probably don't remember. I know that, but..
まぁ　そうだろうな 分かってるけど。
There's only one person who's able to do that.
そんなことできそうなヤツ １人しかいねえから。
It's Fujino Tsukiko What is she?
富士野月子だよ 何？　あいつ　何者なの？
That name is in my memory.
その名前に関しては メモリーが残っています。
No way.. Then who is Fujino Tsukiko?
ウソ… 誰なんだよ　富士野月子って。
It's my name
私の名前です。
Eh?
え？
My name was registered in the past
過去に登録された　私の名前は→
All that time, I was Fujino Tsukiko.
すべて　「富士野月子」です。
What do you mean?
どういうことだよ。
If Kyuto is Fujino Tsukiko, then who is that person?
Ｑ１０が富士野月子だったら じゃあ　あいつは誰なんだ？
All addresses are registered. That's Kanrinin R31 ("kanrinin"= manager, custodian, janitor, landlord)
登録のアドレスは　すべて 「管理人Ｒ３１」です。
Kanrinin R31?
「管理人Ｒ３１」？
Hah? What is that?
はぁ？　何だよ　それ。
I really don't get what you mean right now! So, that is the name of that person?
全然　意味　分かんねえ それが　あいつの名前なの？
Ah~~ It's troublesome if I think too much about it There's no answer to it by the way
何だか　面倒くせぇ　考えたって 答えなんか出ねえよなぁ。
Whoa!
おぉ!?　だ～っ!?
What's so funny?
何が　おかしいのかな？ いや→
When I first saw Kyuto,
Ｑ１０みたいな女のコと 付き合うことなんてさ→
I thought it was ok to go out with you
もう　ないんだろうなと思って。
What's really scary is that someone who doesn't experience sadness
（柳の声）　本当に怖いのは 不幸そのものではありません。
But, the scariest thing is that time
（柳） 一番怖いのは　不幸になった時→
when you stopped thinking about sadness
考えるのを やめてしまうことです。
In other words, your greatest enemy is
つまり　一番の敵は→
is inside you, yourself
自分の中にあるのです。
I wonder if everyone has that fear
（柳）　みんなも　あるんじゃ ないかな？　そういうこと。
Being able to stand up while in panic
パニックになって　立ちすくんで→
not thinking of anything else
何にも 考えられなくなっちゃうこと。
But...
でも…。
“The greatest enemy is inside us”,
＜「一番の敵は　自分の中にある」＞
At that time, I didn't quite understand
＜この言葉の意味を→
the meaning of those words
この時　俺は まるで分かっていなかった＞
I didn't understand
＜俺は　そのことが分からず→
what is that irreplaceable thing
取り返しのつかないことを してしまった＞
My fear during that time
＜あの時　俺は　恐怖で→
I wasn't thinking of anything else but let go of Kyuto's hands
何も考えられず Ｑ１０の手を離してしまった＞
Do you understand? Thinking about death
いいですか？ 死ぬほど考えること。
Don't regret it. It's only a matter of thinking
これが　後悔しない たった一つの　やり方です。
Right
＜そうだ＞
I know what it means to say goodbye forever
＜永遠の別れになると 知りながら→
That is when I let go of the hands of Kyuto again
俺は　Ｑ１０の手を離した＞
EEhhh?! Eh?! Eeehhh?!
（中尾）　えぇ～!?　え!?　えぇ～っ!?
Why? Why is it?! Phone!
何でなんだよ!?　電話！
Eh! Gone! Eh?! I lost my phone? I left it?! I left it!
えっ　ない　え？　電話　忘れた？ 忘れたの？　俺。
Hey, let me borrow your phone... Hey you! Let me borrow your phone!
ねぇ　ちょっと　電話　貸して… ねぇ　君…　電話　貸して！
Let me borrow your phone! Ouch! Let me borrow your phone!
電話　貸して！　痛い痛い… 電話　貸して！
I am really troubled!
（中尾）　僕　ホントに困ります！
Ah! Hello! Hello!
あっ　ちょっと？ もしもし！　もしもし！
Here.. Ah... sorry
（小川　訪）　ほら。 あぁ…　すみません。
What's wrong?
何なの？ あぁ…。
“'The Lunar full throttle" this time, it will be the end..
「『ルナフルスロットル乙』は　今回で 終わりとさせていただきます。
for our loyal readers. Thank you very much"
長らくのご愛読 ありがとうございました」。
This will be the end. NO!! That can't be!
最終回なんだ。 いや～！　違います！
The entire contents didn't tell us that it will be the end!
内容は全然 最終回じゃないんです～！
Aa... you're probably right. This girl here says "Help!" This is probably not the end
あぁ　確かに　「助けてぇぇ!!」で 終わり　これは　ないよな。
The author said that he "can't draw" anymore
作者が 「もう描けない」とかいって→
Instead he went to India! That's the reason why!
インドに 行ってしまったそうなんです！
Really? So even mangaka has difficult times.
あっ　そう？　漫画家も いろいろ大変なんだな。
How am I going to live?!
どうやって生きて行けば いいんですか!?
Eh?
えぇ？
I am supporting Runa-chan with all my heart
ルナちゃんだけが 心の支えだったのに→
How am I going to live from now on?!
これから　どうやって 生きて行けばいいんですか!?
Listen...there is college
あのな　お前　ほら　大学→
You can either choose math or science and then you can make a robot
理数系に変えて ロボット作るんだっつって→
Just study harder so that your grades will go up
お前　頑張って 成績も上がって来たじゃん。
Runa-chan is my high school life.
ルナちゃんあっての高校生活です。
Without Runa-chan, everything returned to darkness
ルナちゃんなき今 すべては闇に返りました。
Hey! You better massage your back! It looks heavy for you!
おい　お前　あんま 思い詰めんじゃねえぞ！
When you open that, something terrible will happen.
((それ　開けるとね 大変なことが起こるよ))
Runa-chan is not in this world...
ルナちゃんのいない世界なんて…。
Useless!
あぁ…　ダメだ　ハァ…。
uwa~
うわ～！
Eh?
（中尾）　えぇ～？
"Welcome back home"
[ﾓﾆﾀ]（恵美子）　「おかえりなさい」。
"Welcome back home!"
[ﾓﾆﾀ]（恵美子）　「おかえりなさい！」。
Uwa~ you're watching it again I'm no good
うわっ　何だ　またこれ。 （影山）　ダメなんだよ。
I feel uncomfortable looking at it. Hey, didn't you notice?
見てないと落ち着かないの。 ねぇ　お前さ　気づいてる？
You're always watching it. I know..
それ　ずっと見てんの。 分かってるよ…。
I'm addicted to it
中毒してるよな　俺。
Then, give it to me.. Let's see if you'll get used to life without this
じゃあさ　ちょっとだけね ない生活に慣れてみようか　ね？
No! No! Impossible! Impossible! Impossible...
ダメダメダメ　無理無理無理！ 無理…。
I'm no good What about?
俺　ダメかも。 何が？
Not worth it as a person
人として　相当ダメかも。
No way!
ウソだぁ！
Are you Kanrinin R31?
あなたが　「管理人Ｒ３１」ですか？
I see.... My name is still recorded in your memory
そっか… 履歴に残ってたんだ　私の名前。
What are you to me?
あなたは　私の何ですか？
I am the one who takes care of you
だから　管理人。
Fukai Heita is the only who takes care of me
私を管理する者は　深井平太です。
That's only for now
今はね。
By the way
そうだ。
Soon enough we'll be leaving this place
もうちょっとしたら ここ　出発するからね。
Are we going somewhere?
どこに行くのですか？
Returning home.
お家に帰るの。
Princess Kaguya went back last month
かぐや姫は月に帰って行きました。
Yup..So I heard What happens then?
（岸本）　うん　そうだけど？ その後は　どうなるのですか？
Hmm..What happens then..
後？　後ねぇ…。
She's probably living happily
月で 幸せに暮らしたんじゃないの？
How is grandpa and grandma doing?
おじいさん　おばあさんは どうしたのですか？
Eh? They were left over to that place
え？　あっ　そっちね 残されたほうか。
Hmmm.. well they're probably lonely out there
うん　まぁ　寂しいだろうけど→
But I know they probably have a lot of pleasant memories
そのうち　いい思い出になって 行ったんじゃないのかなぁ。
Is it alright to have good memories only?
思い出だけで　いいのですかな？
Eh?
え？
They're probably lonely having only good memories
思い出だけじゃ　寂しいよな。
Hmmm..
うん。
But you know, it can't be helped
でもね　しょうがないんだよ。
Meeting someone is the beginning of goodbye You'll eventually say goodbye to someone you met
会うは　別れの始まりなり 会えば別れる。
That's because, that is what human usually do
それは　人間には 必ず　あることなんだから。
Parting?
別れる？
What the heck is this?
（柳）　何だろう？　これ。
This is Fujino Tsukiko's? O..
富士野月子が　これを？ おぉ…。
Ehhh~~ What is this for?
えぇ～？　何のためのもんだろう。
It could be my imagination but I really don't know what it is
僕の気のせいかも しれないんですけど→
When I had this at that time, It's like time went back
これ　持った時 時間が逆戻りしたんですよね。
You mean like a Time Machine? Well...only for about 1 minute
タイムマシーンってこと？ いや　でも　１分ほど。
So what is it? What is it that you're going to tell me?
で？　話って何？
I...
あのさ　俺→
am going to Canada and I'm not going to have a girlfriend there
カナダに行っても 彼女とか　つくらない。
Yup..I'm definitely not getting one
うん　絶対つくんない。
So, I'm telling you not to wait for me or anything like that
あっ　だから待っててほしいとか そういうんじゃないからね。
But...When I come I back and if ever Kawai
でも　もし　帰って来た時　河合が→
doesn't go out with anyone... We don't know what lies ahead
誰とも付き合ってなかったら…。 そんな先のこと　分かんないよ。
We don't even know what will happen 2 months ahead
２か月先のことだって 分かんないのに。
You're right You're right but..
うん　そうだよね そうなんだけど→
what I mean is that my feelings...
でも　俺の気持っていうか…。
Kageyama-kun
影山君さ→
When you come back from Canada, you'll have a job right?
カナダから帰った後って 仕事あるの？
Hm?
え？
Well…I don't know Well time will come when that time comes
いや…　どうだろう まぁ　その時は　その時かな？
I got B grade during the national mock exam
私　全国模試　Ｂだった。
Eh?
え？
This is the first time that I got B. What I mean is, all this time I only got B
Ｂなんて初めて っていうか　この時期にＢって。
Right now, I'm so impatient
もう　今　ものすごい焦ってて→
I want to be honest with you. You probably don't like to listen to me in this room, right?
正直　影山君の話 聞いてる余裕とかないんだよね。
During the exam, I can't hardly remember the "first english word"
この時間あったら　「英単語の 一つでも覚えられるのに」→
..that's what I've been thinking
…って思ってる。
I'm sorry but we are destined to be like this
ごめんね　でも　それが 私達の現実なんだよね。
Can't you face reality more?
ねぇ　もっと現実　見よう。
Kyuto
Ｑ１０。
I've decided to take her back
回収することに決まったから。
I've decided already
もう決まったことだから。
Are you really not Fujino Tsukiko?
本当は 富士野月子じゃないんだろ？
Yup
うん　違うよ。
Then who has the name of Fujino Tsukiko?
「富士野月子」って 誰の名前なんだよ？
That name is supposed to be given to Q10
それはね Ｑ１０につけるはずだった名前。
Q10 is supposed to be Fujino Tsukiko
Ｑ１０が 富士野月子になるはずだったの。
Then mistake happened
手違いがあったの。
We are expecting her to come to our place But she didn't arrived
（月子の声）　本来届くはずの場所に 届かなかった。
When we rushed to get her, she was kidnapped by someone
（月子の声）　私達が駆けつけた時は 誰かに連れ去られた後でね→
Then we found out that she's finally in this place
やっと　ここにいることを 突き止めた。
I was surprised when I knew that she's here
ここにいるって知った時は驚いた。
Even after teaching Q10,
だって私達　Ｑ１０を教育した後→
She withdraws herself from the society
引きこもりの富士野月子として→
Her only goal is be able to come to school
この学校に通わせるのが 目的だったから。
She's always silent and not good in socializing
（月子の声） 無口で人付き合いの悪い 富士野月子としてね。
That is my failure In the end, she ends up in here
手違いはあったけど 結局は　こちらの思う通り→
You see, this why she is able to enter this classroom
教室に入り込めたわけだから→
In this way, we have decided to continue our mission anyway
このまま 任務を継続することにした。
But as for maintenance and data collection, she's not able to do it
でも　メンテナンスとか情報収集が 思うように　できないから→
So, I forced her to be Fujino Tsukiko
私が富士野月子として 乗り込まざるを得なかった。
Now you understand what I mean?
分かってもらえたかな？
What for? Why did you bring
何のためなんだよ？ 何のために　ロボットを→
robot here? What is it for?
ここに　送り込まなきゃ なんなかったんだよ？
Because you're here
ここに　あなたが　いたからよ。
In order for Q10 to meet Fukai Heita
Ｑ１０は 深井平太に会うために→
A robot came here from the future
未来から　やって来た ロボットなの。
Future? What do you mean by that?
「未来」って…　何だよ？　それ。
What do I have something to do about it?
何で　俺なんだよ？
In order to tell you everything, can I hear your request?
全部　話したら 私のお願い　聞いてくれる？
Request?
「お願い」？
Actually it's very simple. Its just that you can't do it
とっても簡単なこと 深井平太にしか　できないこと。
But...
だけど…。
I'm definitely sure that you can't do it
絶対に　やってもらわなきゃ なんないこと。
"From the future"? Do you believe in what she says?
「未来から」って… そんな話　信じられますか？
When I first saw Kyuto, I thought
（柳）　Ｑ１０を初めて見た時 そう思った→
"I can't believe it"
「信じられない」って。
Now, it seems like that it's naturally bound to happen
でも　今は　こうして 当たり前みたいにいる。
I see
ですね。
And now
そして　今は→
you're no longer scared of "what shall I do to stop this"
「いなくなったら　どうしよう」 って怯えてる。
right..
まぁ…。
Fujino Tsukiko said something about "request"?
富士野月子は 「お願い」っていったのよね？
But, when she told me she wanted to hear my "request"
でも 「お願い」っていう割には→
she was like full of herself... like intimidating...
すごい偉そうっていうか 威圧的っていうか…。
In other words,
つまり　それは→
Fukai Heita can hold that as your advantage
深井平太が　アドバンテージを握ってる ってことなんじゃないかなぁ。
no way... I'm not holding anything...
ウソ？ いや　俺　何も握ってないし…。
nor have any powers within me...
っていうか 俺　何の力も持ってないし…。
Why is it that I'm convinced from the start you're telling me that you have no chance of winning?
何で　初めっから こっちに勝ち目がないって→
What is it in the "future"?
思い込んでんのかなぁ。 何で教授は　「未来」とかいってる→
What made you think that I have the chance of winning?
訳の分かんない相手に　勝ち目が あるって思ってんですか？
We don't know until you try!
やってみなきゃ 分かんないからよ！
Just like in any experiments, I don't know what results it may bring
どんな実験だって やってみなきゃ分かんない。
That is why I am doing it
だから　やるの。
hmmm...
ハァ～　う～ん…。
Ah! Can I borrow Kyuto for a while. I have a favor to ask
あっ　Ｑ１０　置いてってくれるかな ちょっと頼みたいことがあんの。
Is it ok with you? Puff.
いいよね？ パフ。
Ok...
うん　じゃあ…。
Kyuto will go back to the place where Fukai Heita is
Ｑ１０の帰る家は　深井平太です。
I know..
うん　分かってる。
It'll be fine, I'm thinking the same way
大丈夫　俺も　そう思ってるから。
Is there a place for me to win?
勝ち目なんて　どこにあるんだよ。
Fujioka-kun, your father is here
（店長） 藤丘君　おとうさん　来てるよ。
Eh? My father?
（藤丘）　え？　俺ですか？ うん。
Oh
（藤丘の父）　おう。
Why?
何で？
I heard from Hayato that you worked here
ここで働いてるって勇人に聞いて。
Your mother was hospitalized
かあさん　入院した。
Eh? hospitalized?
え？　「入院」って？
Yeah, pancreatitis
うん　膵炎。
She's not dying or something
死ぬとか　そんなんじゃないから。
You see, there are a lot of hospital charges
でも　ほら　入院費とか いろいろ　かかっちゃってさ。
So...somehow do you have something there?
お前　何とかなんないかな？
"somehow"?
「何とか」って…。
Can I..
だから　ここ…→
borrow some money from you? That's impossible!
前借りとか…。 無理に決まってるだろ！
I just recently worked here
入ったばっかりなんだし。
I see
そっか　そうだよなぁ。
Aa~~ I'm running out of luck
あ～　弱っちゃったなぁ。
I'm really hopeless. Misfortunes keep on coming
「弱り目に祟り目」とは このこったなぁ。
How much do you want?
いくらなんだよ？
Eh?
ん？
How much? How much it should be?
いくら？ いくらあればいいんだよ。
About 300,000 yen
うん　まぁ　３０万円くらいかなぁ。
That much?
そんなに？
She had operation
手術とかするらしくってさ。
I see
そう。
Oh...what did your father say?
おう　おとうさん　何だって？
He's in the neighborhood,  so he just passed by
あっ　あの　近くに寄ったからって。
Oh ... ok
あっ　そう。
Ano... Hm?
あの…。 ん？
Well…
いや…。
Kubo-kun! Are you alright? Kubo-kun!
（看護師） 久保君！　大丈夫？　久保君！
There is an accident here doctor. Please come!
急変です　先生　お願いします！
Kubo-kun! Are you alright? The doctor is coming!
久保君！ 大丈夫　もう先生　来るからね！
I'm done for~~
（小川しげ） あぁ～　あ～　もう終わりだ。
it's no use... I'm home!
もうダメ…。 ≪ただいま≫
It's a present. I've brought you canned peaches I'm sorry~
買って来たよ　桃の缶詰。 すまないねぇ。
It's still warm. Do you want to eat it? Yup
冷えてないけど　食べる？ うん。
I...
ハァ～　私→
think I'm going to die this way~~
このまま 死んじゃうのかしらね～。
Is it really that good to die?
そんなに　うまく 死ねるわけねえだろうがよ。
Aren't you going to drink medicine?
薬　のんだの？
I'll put it here
はい　ここ置いとくよ。
Feed me~~
食べさせて～。
Hah?! You're really a bothersome old hag!
はぁ～？ ホント　面倒くせぇババアだな。
Not good
あ～　もうダメだ。
Not good! Not good...I'm going to die~
ダメだ　ダメだ　死ぬ～…！ [TEL]（着信音）
Oh Yamamoto?
あっ　山本？
Hello.. what is it?
はい　何？
I got a phone call...look...
[TEL]（民子） 電話あったんです！　ほら→
your friend who works in music industry
先生の友達の 音楽の仕事してるって人に→
called me and he introduced himself
電話してくれたじゃないですか あの人の紹介で→
He told us to send our song "Aitai" to one of the music producer
音楽プロデューサーに　私達の曲　送ったら 「会いたい」って…！
Really! I'll listen to your stories in detail later
あっ　そう！ 何だ　話　進んでんじゃんかよ。
Ah... Don't do unnecessary things anymore
うん… あっ　でもな　ダメもとだからな。
just because it didn't turn out well. Don't disappoint me
うまく行かなかったからって ガッカリすんじゃねえぞ。
Yup...Ok...Ok...good for you Ok..Ok~
うん…　あぁ　はいはい　よかったな は～い　は～い。
I can't hardly eat~
食べさして～…。
Jezz..I'm already in hell..
もう　地獄絵図だわ。
Kubo-kun!
久保君！
Kubo-kun?
久保君？
He's in ICU right now Did something bad happen?
今　集中治療室。 悪いんですか？
Sorry, I'm not allowed to meet anyone
ごめんね　今日は会えないわ。
What is "reality"?
現実って何なんだよ！
Don't say things that is not possible for me to do!!
んなこと　いわれたって 何にも　できねえよ～!!
What is "reality"?...
何なんだよ　現実って…。
Ah! I lost again!
（深井武広）　あぁ　また負けたよ！ （深井千秋）　アハハハ…！
I'm home~ Welcome back~
ただいま～。 （深井ほなみ）　おかえり～。
Welcome back...your girlfriend is here
おかえり　彼女　来てるよ。
Girlfriend?
彼女？
Hey..you did something good~
（武広） おい　お前　いいとこあんじゃん。
That child is good She didn't stop talking
（ほなみ）　この子 家じゃ　何にも喋んないの。
Take kindly to the seclusion in class
（武広）　引きこもってて クラスに　なじめなかったの→
I wonder if there are forces here and there given to you?
お前　いろいろ 力になってあげたんだろ？
Well… What's with that face!
いや…。 （武広）　何だよ　その顔！
He's like a shy guy
こいつね　照れ屋なの。
Do you like to eat? Today, all foods are home fried
あっ　そうだ　ご飯　食べてく？ 家ね　今日　空揚げなんだけど。
Okay
あっ　はい。
Alright! alright! Let's go eat! Let's go eat!
（武広）　よしよしよし！ 食べてこう　食べてこう！
Why did you came? I need to talk to you ASAP
何しに来たんだよ？ 至急　連絡したいことがあったの。
Early tomorrow morning, could you come to the classroom?
明日の朝早く 教室に来てくれるかな。
Together with Kyuto. Why?
Ｑ１０と一緒に。 何のために？
I'll tell you all the secrets of Kyuto
Ｑ１０の秘密　全部　教えてあげる。
Why so sudden?
何だよ　急に。
You don't want to know?
知りたくない？
It's really scary to find out the truth right?
本当のこと知ってしまうのって 怖いもんね。
Will Fukai-kun's heart be able to handle it well?
深井君の心臓　フフっ　持つかな？
Tomorrow then.
じゃあ　明日ね。
Well then..
（月子）　≪さてと≫
What do you want us to tell you?
何から教えてほしいのかな？
In order for Kyuto to meet me, she came here..
Ｑ１０が　俺に会うために ここに来たって→
What's that supposed to mean?
どういうことだよ。
The world after 70 years
７０年後の世界→
In other words, Q10 came from 2080
つまり　Ｑ１０は ２０８０年から　やって来た。
You still have the incurable disease 70 years after
７０年先にも　治らない病気って まだ　あってね→
We saw that people are looking forward to die but
私達　そういう 死ぬのを待つだけの人達を→
there is one person who wants to go back to the past. So, I gave her what she wanted
一番戻りたい過去へ 連れて行ってあげるの。
It has been difficult for her to cross over
だけど　時空を越えるのは とても過酷なことなの。
So, in exchange, we substituted a robot that can go back from time to time
だから　代わりにロボットが 戻りたい時代まで　さかのぼって→
And that person continued watching the videos sent to her
その人が見たかった映像を 送り続ける。
That was our job
それが私達の仕事。
Then..
じゃあ→
through Kyuto, my images are seen. To whom did you send it?
俺の映像を　Ｑ１０を通して 未来に送ってたってこと？
Who?
誰に？
You send it to whom?
誰に送ってたんだよ？
Your wife
あなたの奥さんよ。
My wife?
奥さん？
Yup. You got married
（月子）　そう　結婚するの。
But 70 years later you had a serious illness
だけど　７０年後 重い病気に　かかってしまう。
"She wanted to see you in your younger years"
「出会う前の １０代のあなたに会いたい」。
That was her last wish
それが　彼女の最後の望みだった。
She was very happy for what she received
とっても満足してもらったわ。
Received?
「もらった」って…。
Yes. So our task has ended
そう　もう　その任務は終わったの。
Then your wife died
奥さんは　亡くなったの。
When?
いつだよ？
When did that happen?
いつの話なんだよ？
Do want to see the last video that your wife saw?
奥さんが最期に見た映像　見る？
Kyuto is now sleepy
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　Ｑ１０　眠くなりました。
W...wait a minute
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　ちょ…　ちょっと待って！
During this time... She died while watching this?
この時に… これ見ながら死んだってこと？
Her last words were...
最期の言葉は…。
"Heita, let's meet again"
「平太　また会おうね」。
Heita, let's meet again
（女性の声）　平太　また会おうね。
Kyuto came in to your younger years
（月子）　Ｑ１０は　１０代のあなたを 奥さんに届けるために→
for the sake of your wife
やって来たの。
Fukai and Fujino Tsukiko are together. What are they doing so early this morning?
（唯）　深井さ　富士野月子と 朝早くから何やってんだろ？
At this time? How suspicious! Indeed!
（宮沢）　こんな時間に？　怪しい！ （西村）　だよな。
In other words, our mission has ended
つまり　これで私達の任務は終了。
You want to go back to 2080 as soon as possible right?
早く ２０８０年に帰りたいんだよね。
But, in order to do that, you have to press
でも　そのためには　深井平太に→
Kyuto's reset button. Can you do that?
Ｑ１０の　リセットボタンを 押してもらわなきゃ　ダメなの。
Can you press the reset button?
押してくれるかな？ リセットボタン。
I don't want to
嫌だ。
I see.. As expected you don't have the power to do it.
そっか　やっぱり 力ずくじゃないとダメなの。
Ah! Fukai-kun be careful! That ball..
あっ！　深井君　気をつけて そのボール…。
No! Remove your hands!
ダメ！　手　離して！
Don't touch that!
離すの！
Thinking about death
死ぬほど考えるの。
Don't regret it! It's just a matter of thinking!
それが　後悔しない たった一つの　やり方よ！
Professor…Professor?
教授…　教授？
Where did professor go?
教授を　どこやったんだよ？
She's hopping in different space and time Bring her back right now!
いろんな時空を飛び回っている。 戻せよ　今すぐ!!
Then, press Kyuto's reset button
じゃあ　Ｑ１０をリセットして。
After pressing the reset button, professor will come back right away
リセットボタン押したら 教授は　すぐに戻す。
As I said,
いったでしょ→
"It's difficult to cross over through time"
「時空を移動するのは とても過酷なことだ」って。
If she can't come back right away, her body will be worn out
すぐに戻さないと　教授の体 ボロボロになっちゃうよ。
Is it ok for you if that happens to professor?
教授が　どうなってもいいの？
You don't have much time to think about it
考えてる時間なんて ないんだからね。
Kyuto...
Ｑ１０…→
I'm sorry
ごめん。
Thank you
ありがとう。
Now we can return to year 2080
これで　私達 ２０８０年に帰れるわ。
Bring back professor right now
早く教授　戻せよ。
So you finally pressed it..
そっか　押したんだ→
the reset button
リセットボタン。
Thank you for your hard work professor
教授　お疲れさまでした。
I..
俺…。
If given that situation, anybody will press the rest button
あの場合　誰だって リセットボタン　押すわよ。
I...
俺…→
When professor disappeared,
教授が消えて→
I was really scared..
ただ怖くて…。
Just only that. I wasn't able to think of anything else...
それだけで　もう 何も考えられなくなって…。
I wasn't aware that I pressed the reset button...
気づいたら リセットボタン　押してて…。
That frustrates me
それが悔しくて。
Doing it not thinking twice...
あんな簡単に…。
I'm not even resisting...
俺　何の抵抗もしなくて…。
I see.. She returned to the place she belong
（岸本） そうか　戻るべき所に戻ったのか。
year 2080?.. Anybody will be blown away with that story
２０８０年って… 何か　ぶっ飛んだ話だなぁ。
I wasn't able to do much anyway
どのみち　ず～っとは いられなかったんだよな。
You're lying It's a lie! It's a lie! It's a lie!
ウソだろ？ ウソだ　ウソだ　ウソだ。
It's definitely a lie I'll never believe it!
絶対ウソだ そんなの俺　絶対　信じねえし。
It's the truth
ホントなんだ。
I pressed the reset button
俺が　リセットボタン　押した。
Why did you do such thing?!
何で　そんなことしたんだよ!?
Sorry.
ごめん。
Even Runa-chan has ended... And on top of that Kyuto too...
ルナちゃんだって終わったんだぞ その上　Ｑ１０まで…。
There's no way for me to believe in what you said!
あり得ないよ　そんな話。
You're lying! You're lying! Definitely not possible!
ウソだ　ウソだ　ウソだ！ 絶対あり得ないし！
Kyuto left this for you
Ｑ１０が お前に残してったらしい。
Don't blame yourself for what happened
あんまり　自分を責めんなよ？
Well, it was a good thing that it happened You'll be alright in no time
まぁ　でも　よかったよ まだ　お前が無事でさ。
If not for Professor Yanagi,
柳教授じゃなくて もし　お前だったらさ→
In your heart, you'll never know what it is like to be separated to someone
ここんとこ　どうなってたか 分かんなかったわけだし。
Professor Yanagi also said "she was glad that she was able to time travel"
柳教授も「時間旅行ができた」って 喜んでたし。
Yup. It's a good thing that it happened
うん　よかったんだよ。
Fukai Heita is now verified
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　深井平太を認証しました。
We own this whole town~ I get it. This is our town
ぜ～んぶ　俺達の町。 [ﾓﾆﾀ] 分かった　そう　俺達の町だ。
You're so close
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　近いよ。
"world"
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　「世界」。
The world is born
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　世界が生まれました。
Heita's grass Leaves?
平太　草。 [ﾓﾆﾀ] 葉っぱ。
Are you alright?~
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　だ～いじょ～ぶれ～すか？
gentleman who totally does not understand how to have sympathy for people.
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　人の情けの 分からないお方です。
Didn't I say, "anything would be fine"?
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　俺　「どうでもいい」って いっただけじゃん。
Ga~~n
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　ガ～ン。
I just happened to press your button
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　俺　たまたま 押しただけだもんな。
But Heita pressed it
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　でも　平太が押した。
Young master... Hm?
若旦那。 [ﾓﾆﾀ] ん？
Did you have a change of heart?
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　心を入れ替えたのですか？
What will you do when you cry?
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　泣きたくなったら どうすんの？
When I remember Heita, I smile instead
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　平太のことを思い出して 代わりに笑います。
Don't make promises
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　約束は　しません。
I believe in Heita all this time
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　いつ　いかなる時も Ｑ１０は平太を信じます。
Kyuto is sleepy now
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　Ｑ１０　眠くなりました。
It's already this time...
もう　こんな時間。
Q-chan?!
Ｑちゃん!?
I'm here to charge
充電しに来ました。
A~ you surprised me!
あ～ら　ビックリした。
So...it's Professor Yanagi
何だ…　柳教授。
I see..
（しげ）　そういや→
Tsukiko or Kawai chan
今朝　月子とかいう かわいい女のコが→
or Q-chan came for a visit
Ｑちゃんを訪ねて来ましたよ。
Really?
そうですか。
I said "she's not here anymore"
「もう　いないのよ」っていったら→
and she said "I see" And then I realized, I miss her.
「そうですか」って 寂しそうにしてました。
Is it ok that I'll come once in a while to charge?
時々 充電しに来ても　いいですか？
Yes..As you wish
どうぞ　どうぞ。
Whoa!!!
うわぁ～～!!
Nakao-kun! lend me your strength to retrieve Kyuto back!
中尾君　力を貸して Ｑ１０を取り戻すの！
Eh? What?! What do you mean?!
えぇ!?　何？　どういうこと？
"Nakao-kun lend me your strength to retrieve Kyuto back"?
「中尾君　力を貸して Ｑ１０を取り戻すの」？
EEhh?! What do you mean? Eh?!
えぇ!?　どういうこと？　えぇ!?
Kyuto will go back to a place where Heita is
[ﾓﾆﾀ]　Ｑ１０の帰る家は 深井平太です。
Kyuto, right now I am
＜Ｑ１０　俺は今→
repeatedly flooded with drifting waves of regret
繰り返し　押し寄せて来る 後悔の波の中を漂っている＞
I'm supposed to do something? No...I wasn't able to do anything
＜何か　できたんじゃないか？ いや　何もできなかった＞
Will I really be ok with that?
＜ホントに あれでよかったのか？＞
No.. but I really did it
＜いや　あれしかなかったんだ＞
In this dark sea where there is no answer
＜正解のない　暗い海を→
I can't hold on to anything that is drifting
俺は　つかまるものもなく 漂っている＞
Why is it that during that time,
＜何で　あの時→
all I think was "I can't do anything" and then give up that easily?
「何もできない」と 諦めてしまったんだろう＞
I came to help!
（中尾）　助けに来ました！
You came after all! I will do everything to help!
やっぱり来てくれたんだ。 俺　何でもやりますから！
If I'm going to regret it,
＜こんなに後悔するんなら→
then why do I have this feeling that I can do something
何だって　できたはずなのに＞
Why can't I stop thinking about it?
＜何で俺は　考えるのを やめてしまったんだろう＞
Kyuto!
Ｑ１０！
These are my tears. From now on, I will not cry anymore.
((私の涙です これで　私は　もう泣きません))
Well, you will not cry forever?
((いや　だって 一生　泣かないってこと？))
Forever
((一生です))
That's not the one. That's not Kyuto
違う　Ｑ１０じゃ　ない。
Who is it then?
じゃあ　誰なんだ？
Who is that girl that I saw right now?
今の誰なんだよ。
Thinking about death
＜死ぬほど考えること＞
Don't regret it. It's just a matter of thinking
＜それが　後悔しない たった一つの　やり方＞
This box of DVDs
この番組のＤＶＤボックスを→
will be given to 10 lucky winners
抽選で１０名の方に プレゼントいたします。
Please visit our homepage. Puff
詳しくは　ホームページを ご覧ください。 パフ。
Next week is finally the last episode right?
え～　そして　ついに来週は 最終回ですね。
Don't miss it Yes you're right
お見逃しなく。 はい　そういうことです。